Kristen Lucas

Data Analyst

Nashville, TN 37208

Professional Profile

Data Analyst with a passion for using data to create understandable visuals to help make sound business decisions. Motivated, versatile worker with over 15 years of experience in the workplace. Proven record of excellence in fast-paced, often chaotic, environments. Especially skilled at creating and following a goal-oriented plan while making necessary adaptations to ensure an excellent result. While getting a job done well, who ever said you can't have fun at the same time?! We are living in a world where data is the future, and I'm excited to be a part of it.

Phone: 520-548-9690

Email: kristenw629@gmail.com

Github - https://github.com/KristenLucas

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristen-lucas-b1520311a/

Technical Skills

- SQL PostgreSQL, BigQuery
- Advanced Excel experience
- Intermediate Python ability
- Effective Visualizations Power BI, Tableau, Excel

Other Skills

- Full Microsoft Suite knowledge/ability
- Github, including Kanban boards
- SalesForce & Outreach experience
- Clear communication
- Effective storytelling

Data Analytics Experience

Nashville Software School

Grad Date - Jan 2021

Six month, intensive, apprenticeship school focused on practical training in data analysis using real-world projects and visualizations.

Projects (Github's are linked):

Capstone - The Air We Breathe (Excel, SQL, Tableau)

There are few things the entire world has in common, but breathing and the need for clean air is one of them. I wanted to see how the USA compares to other countries in terms of air quality, then look at large cities within the US. Then I wanted to take a look at Nashville and how we compare to other cities. This was my personal project from start to finish. I found the data, cleaned it in Excel (four of the data sets had over 150,000 rows), analyzed and transformed the data in SQL, and visualized the presentation in Tableau.

Nashville 911 Calls and Dispatch (Python, Excel)

Our entire class performed an analysis of 911 calls and dispatch data during some of the most devastating natural disasters in Nashville in recent years: The tornados on March 3rd, 2020, and the derecho on May 3rd, 2020. We mapped many things including the times of calls vs dispatch, most affected areas by zip code, and any correlation between COVID-19 and these events. We were split into four teams. I was out team's leader and I managed our Kanban board to ensure all tasks were completed in the proper time.

Lahman Baseball (PostgresSQL)

Analysis of baseball players, managers, stats, salaries, and more from the years 1876-2016. This project consisted of 27 tables and required multiple joins on most queries.

Work Experience

<u>Sip Café – Nashville, TN</u>

Aug 2019 – Present

Local café in East Nashville specializing in locally roasted coffee and house-made ice cream.

Barista/Shift Leader

- While leading up to 4 people, improved wait time by approximately 25% by keeping staff on task and ensuring efficiency, excellence, and customer satisfaction.
- Accurately track tip money throughout day and distribute to staff in a timely manner.
- Brainstormed with manager to help create 5 new policies to implement in response to COVID-19.

Ramsey Solutions, Endorsed Local Provider (ELP) Division - Nashville, TN

July 2016 - Aug 2019

Nashville based financial solutions company focused on helping people in every walk of life to better their finances.

Real Estate ELP- Customer Advocate

- Communicated with customers to ensure Real Estate ELPs met specific obligations.
- Was awarded Customer Advocate of the Month four times each year by demonstrating that I could determine customer problems and ensure a resolution.

- Managed my own calendar to maintain goal of up to 90 calls per day, respond to all voicemails and emails within 24 hours, and attend mandatory meetings.
- Assisted in the training of 5 new team members.

Raging Sage Coffee Roaster - Tucson, AZ

Sept 2011 - May 2016

Local coffee shop specializing in coffee roasted in-house and baked goods made in-house.

Assistant Manager (July 2012-May 2016)

- Served as liaison between manager and staff of approximately 30 employees over the duration of position.
- Assisted manager in the process of hiring by conducting approximately 45 face-to-face and working interviews.
- Functioned as lead trainer for 15 new baristas.
- Increased weekly tips by 20% by implementing a creative "This vs That" tip jar contest.

Barista/Baker (Sept 2011-May 2016)

- Effectively worked as a team and maintained high level of excellence in fast-paced environment of up to 60 customers per hour.
- Followed specific instructions to create a high volume of product in bakery: up to 120 items per day.
- Built relationships with regular patrons and memorized approximately 75% of their orders.

Teen Challenge's Springboard Home for Youth in Crisis - Tucson, AZ

Jan 2011 - Sept 2011

Recovery/rehabilitation group home for girls ages 12-17.

Group Home Houseparent

- Ensured adherence to daily schedule and maintained proper distribution and documentation of medications for up to 15 girls at a time.
- Recorded detailed observations of up to 8 residents per day for reference by counselors.
- Maintained confidentiality in accordance with state law.

Central City Assembly of God - Tucson, AZ

Aug 2010 - May 2016

Church in Tucson of around 100 members.

Associate Pastor/Administrator

- Analyzed finances and helped create yearly budget that relieved financial strain and doubled church's ministry capacity.
- Managed up to forty volunteers at various gatherings and events.
- Assisted Lead Pastor in any capacity necessary, including delivering sermons and/or seminars approximately five times a
 year.

Education

Nashville Software School Expected Graduation:

Six month, intensive, apprenticeship school focused on practical training in Jan 2021 data analysis using real-world projects and visualizations.

Berean School of the Bible Aug 2011 – Aug 2013

Global University correspondence

Assembly of God school where I received Certification Credentials.

Master's Commission USA Sept 2006 – May 2010

Ministry apprenticeship program. I was a student for 2 years, then on staff for 2 years.